

# FIRAT IŞILDAK

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

firatisildak1@gmail.com +90 551-648 38 13 Portfolio Github m Linkedin







iZMİR / Türkiye

**GPA: 3.08** 

### **EDUCATION**



Computer Engineering 2020 - 2024 IskenderunTechnical University

I've completed my undergraduate studies at Iskenderun Technical University, focusing on backend areas such as SQL, database management, Java, C#, C++, and C. With a solid foundation in computer engineering, I've gained a deep understanding of backend technologies. My education has equipped me with the skills to tackle challenges in both hardware and software domains, and I'm eager to apply my knowledge and expertise in practical settings.

#### **SKILLS**

.Net

SOL

**Entity Framework** 

ASP.NET Core

C#

Git/Github

Database Management

· Clean architecture **CQRS Pattern** 

Solid Principles

Web API

 HTML AND CSS BootStrap

Blazor

### **LANGUAGES**

İngilizce :

Turkish:

Mative

### **CERTIFICATES**

- PeopleBox WebApp Bootcamp: Techcareer.net
- Dev Talks: CODERSPACE
- Asp.Net Core Web API: BTK Akademi
- API AND API TESTING: BTK Akademi
- SQL Server in All Aspects: BTK Akademi
- Modern web development course: UDEMY
- Html and CSS: UDEMY
- English Education: UDEMY

# REFERENCES

#### Robin Şahin

Frontend Developer-in Sweden

+46 722983593

# **ABOUT ME**

Computer Engineering graduate from Iskenderun Technical University, specializing in Microsoftbased technologies. Proficient in C#, .NET, ASP.NET Core, Web API, .NET MAUI, Blazor, SQL, and SQL Server. Experienced in Clean Architecture, MVVM, and layered architecture. Primarily focused on backend development with full-stack capabilities using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap. Continuously improving by following technological advancements.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER - FULL TIME**

**GESTEK** Geotek Proje Otomasyon 27/08/2024 - Present

At Geotek Automation, I gained experience in Microsoft-based technologies, working with C#, .NET, ASP.NET Core, Web API, .NET MAUI, and Blazor. I developed expertise in SQL and SQL Server while applying design patterns like Clean Architecture, MVVM, and layered architecture. Primarily focused on backend development, I also contributed to frontend using HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap, enhancing my full-stack development skills.

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER INTERN**



Sanal Yazılım 02/03/2023 - 17/08/2023

My education focused mainly on backend development, so I initially felt lacking in frontend skills. However, during my internship, I improved my user interface skills with JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. I also recognized the importance of teamwork and communication in the software industry. This experience not only advanced my technical knowledge but also improved my organizational skills and dedication, helping me become a better team player. Additionally, I refined my backend skills, particularly in the efficient and optimized use of PHP.

### FREELANCER DEVELOPER



Feydas Company 06/02/2023 - 17/08/2023

Developed a web application for Feydas Company to optimize invoice management, enhancing efficiency and reducing time loss. Built a responsive frontend with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and JavaScript, while implementing secure backend logic with PHP.

### **PROJECTS**

# **WEB API**

This project is an enterprise-level Web API solution developed using the C# programming language and .NET platform. The project is built on the ASP.NET framework and utilizes Entity Framework for database operations. Additionally, Autofac library is used to implement the Inversion of Control (IoC principle, and necessary structures for JWT token-based authentication processes are integrated.

I INK: https://github.com/Firatisildak/MyFinalProject

#### **EDUCATION SALES**

This project is a prototype of an online education sales site developed using front-end technologies such as HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap, with back-end (backend) operations performed using PHP. The project also includes animated designs using JavaScript. MySQL is used for database operations.

• LINK: <a href="https://github.com/Firatisildak/EducationSales">https://github.com/Firatisildak/EducationSales</a>